<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Alices Digital Notebook</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Alices Digital Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 19:16:50 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alicela1n.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I don't recommend Manjaro Linux</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-10-18-manjarno/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 19:16:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-10-18-manjarno/</guid><description>Introduction So on Twitter as a response to a tweet by Linus Tech Tips showing Linus&amp;rsquo;s frustration with Linux, I quoted the tweet saying &amp;ldquo;This is why you don&amp;rsquo;t use Manjaro&amp;rdquo;. That got many responses, a lot from Manjaro users telling me how great Manjaro is. Now I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect that tweet to get as much attention as it did, or cause controversy. I respect people&amp;rsquo;s distro choices, and I think Linux is all about freedom of choice, and people should have the choice to use whatever distro they want to use.</description></item><item><title>Installing Gentoo on the Pentium III</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-09-18-installing-gentoo-on-the-pentium-iii/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 19:16:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-09-18-installing-gentoo-on-the-pentium-iii/</guid><description>This blog post targets EXPERIENCED Gentoo users only, I&amp;rsquo;m not helping you, and you are on your own! The future is uncertain, since this setup involves using old versions of some packages, and patches for others, it&amp;rsquo;s uncertain whether or not it&amp;rsquo;ll work tomorrow, or whether or not you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to update this install in the future, so use at your own risk!
This post is not 100% complete, but if I don&amp;rsquo;t upload it now I won&amp;rsquo;t ever.</description></item><item><title>Why I use Arch Linux</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-09-17-why-i-use-arch-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 17:16:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-09-17-why-i-use-arch-linux/</guid><description>Introduction So as you know, I use Arch Linux with the KDE Plasma desktop environment. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a few other distros, like Gentoo, Fedora, Debian and I&amp;rsquo;ve always eventually come back to Arch Linux. I decided to write this blog post to get into some of the reasons why that is.
Rolling Release This is a huge thing for me, I love rolling release distros, and I love having access to the latest software.</description></item><item><title>Learning to Love Vim</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-09-12-learning-to-love-vim/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 17:45:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-09-12-learning-to-love-vim/</guid><description>Introduction When I first learned about Vim I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very enthusiastic about it, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very open minded and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use it because I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to use it. However, things have changed, and I&amp;rsquo;m now using vim as my primary editor! I used to use Text Wrangler (back when I used a MacBook), then switched over to Visual Studio Code when I switched over to using Linux, I eventually settled on using Sublime Text, and still do use it for larger projects.</description></item><item><title>Installing Gentoo</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-08-26-installing-gentoo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 23:45:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-08-26-installing-gentoo/</guid><description>Introduction Gentoo is a source based Linux distribution which is very flexible and can be customized to fit the user&amp;rsquo;s needs. A bit ago I started using Gentoo Linux daily. EDIT: Back to using Arch Linux. Here&amp;rsquo;s the install procedure, because a lot of people seem to think it&amp;rsquo;s difficult.
Creating a live USB Obviously before we can begin, we need to boot the computer into some kind of environment. I opt for systemrescuecd.</description></item><item><title>Using Wayland daily on KDE Plasma, My Experience</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-07-14-using-wayland-daily-on-plasma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 09:30:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-07-14-using-wayland-daily-on-plasma/</guid><description>Introduction Ever since KDE Plasma 5.21 it&amp;rsquo;s been fully usable under Wayland. To the point where I never need to boot back into Xorg anymore! KDE Plasma is my favorite desktop environment, atm. Plasma for a long time was the one thing holding me back from using Wayland. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that stable, and the experience on Xorg was overall far less buggy. Xorg is slowly going away, Wayland is the future.</description></item><item><title>Case Study: Updating old install of Arch Linux</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-07-05-updating-old-archlinux-install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 15:12:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-07-05-updating-old-archlinux-install/</guid><description>Introduction So there&amp;rsquo;s this myth that if Arch Linux gets too old then you can&amp;rsquo;t update the install anymore. I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly know what classifies as &amp;ldquo;too old&amp;rdquo; since I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to update installs up to 2 years out of date. However, I decided to go a step further and update an install that&amp;rsquo;s 5 years out of date.
Problems The best way to avoid running into serious problems is to read the Arch Linux news letter as it typically tells you how to fix any problems you may run into.</description></item><item><title>How to switch from Windows to Linux</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-06-15-linux-guide-for-windows-users/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 15:12:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-06-15-linux-guide-for-windows-users/</guid><description>Warning Before getting into this it is assumed all your important data is backed up somewhere, whether that&amp;rsquo;s a cloud service, or external device, this WILL wipe all your data, and I&amp;rsquo;m not responsible for anything that goes wrong!
Introduction Microsoft announced their new Windows 11, (correction: the new Windows 11 was leaked, not officially announced) I hate it. This inspired me to write a blog post to help Windows users switch over from Windows 10 to Linux, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be focusing on Kubuntu.</description></item><item><title>Using Kubuntu on my old MacBook Pro</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-04-11-kubuntu-on-old-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 11:23:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-04-11-kubuntu-on-old-macbook-pro/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve used a 2010 MacBook Pro as my main laptop for a couple years, it&amp;rsquo;s old, slow, and the last version of macOS to support it is 10.13.6. I replaced my MacBook a little over a year ago, so it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been doing much lately. Introduction So macOS 10.13, it&amp;rsquo;s ancient, at this point a lot of applications are dropping support, and it&amp;rsquo;s happening really fast too. I still use my 2010 MacBook Pro as my secondary laptop because it&amp;rsquo;s still quite useful as a little 13&amp;quot; laptop.</description></item><item><title>Installing Gentoo on Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-04-06-gentoo-on-pi-4-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 11:12:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-04-06-gentoo-on-pi-4-notes/</guid><description>Introduction If you remember Sakaki&amp;rsquo;s Gentoo images for the Raspberry Pi 4, they were great. It was one of the best performing distros for the Raspberry Pi 4. Since Sakaki no longer updates them they are effectively dead.
Gentoo is one of my favorite Linux distros because of it&amp;rsquo;s insane level of customization and control, over just about everything. In the make.conf you have a lot of control over your installation.</description></item><item><title>Linux troubles again...</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-03-22-linux-troubles-again/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 20:59:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-03-22-linux-troubles-again/</guid><description>Linux troubles again, this time it&amp;rsquo;s my audio that&amp;rsquo;s not working. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even realize it wasn&amp;rsquo;t working for a while. Then it randomly hit me, no audio. Obviously, this is not enough to convince me to switch to Windows, as I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of that operating system. However it is really annoying so I&amp;rsquo;m gonna have to try and fix it.
Diagnosing the problem Let&amp;rsquo;s see what shows up in /proc/asound/card0</description></item><item><title>Tegra 3 unbricking notes</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-02-05-tegra-3-unbrick-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 15:09:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2021-02-05-tegra-3-unbrick-notes/</guid><description>This is just a quick little post to keep notes for how I unbricked my ASUS MemoPad ME301T.
Tegra 3 unbricking Using tegra 3 unbrick I managed to unbrick the MemoPad.
Enter APX mode Different depending on device.
Pwning the bootrom # ./fusee-launcher/fusee-launcher.py ./payload/uart_payload_n7.bin -P 7330 Is your BCT Good? If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Nexus 7 or Ouya you&amp;rsquo;ll need a BCT. You can dump it with:
# ./utils/nvflash_v1.13.87205 --getbct --bct BCT_READBACK_N7.</description></item><item><title>I decided to install Gentoo</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-12-18-when-i-decide-to-install-gentoo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 12:15:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-12-18-when-i-decide-to-install-gentoo/</guid><description>I rarely if ever update this blog, maybe once every few months. Anyways I might one day find the motivation to get back into blogging, who knows these days. Anyways I decided to write this post because I&amp;rsquo;m using Gentoo now, a source based Linux distro.
Why Gentoo? I was using Arch for a while, then started looking into Gentoo. I liked the way it&amp;rsquo;s package management works, being source based.</description></item><item><title>Make your own dotfiles repo today</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-10-31-make-your-own-dotfiles-repo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 12:15:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-10-31-make-your-own-dotfiles-repo/</guid><description>Introduction Dotfiles, we all love them. If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me and use the command line a lot you surely use dotfiles. Things like your vimrc, zshrc, tmux config, etc are all dotfiles.
So why should you make a repo with your dotfiles? A github repo including all your dotfiles makes it easier to deploy them later, also makes it possible for other people to use them. I get asked occasionally, &amp;ldquo;how did you make your setup look like that?</description></item><item><title>Working audio in Mac OS X 10.5 (or 10.4) PPC in QEMU</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-08-23-osx-10.5-ppc-in-qemu-with-working-audio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 11:12:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-08-23-osx-10.5-ppc-in-qemu-with-working-audio/</guid><description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in old operating systems in a while, especially Apple ones. I love QEMU because it lets me emulate different (and a lot of obscure) operating systems and architectures that I otherwise would not have access to. This includes PPC Mac OS X, however one problem is that audio has never worked for me, since QEMU doesn&amp;rsquo;t emulate a supported sound card.
Passing through an audio device? Inconvenient, and I need to find one that is supported first.</description></item><item><title>Need to use a different Linux distro? Just systemd-nspawn it!</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-08-22-just-systemd-nspawn-it/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 08:00:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-08-22-just-systemd-nspawn-it/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux on my main computer for over a year and a half now, distro hopping because I always somehow find something wrong with the distro I&amp;rsquo;m using. Whether it be that I need to use a different version of the GCC compiler than the one in the distro&amp;rsquo;s repos or something else. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying Ubuntu, Debian, Arch, Gentoo, and some other ones like Fedora, Manjaro, openSUSE, Void Linux but none of them seemed to solve the problems I was having where I always need access to a package not in that distro&amp;rsquo;s repositories, Arch is the best right for me right now because it has the AUR (Arch User Repository) which has most stuff but not everything.</description></item><item><title>Dumping SHSH and restoring 32bit iOS device</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-06-26-dumping-shsh-and-restoring-iphone-without-losing-ios-version/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 23:48:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-06-26-dumping-shsh-and-restoring-iphone-without-losing-ios-version/</guid><description>!This was one of my quick written guides so if you have any improvements feel free to pull request them in!
Introduction Sometimes you might be in a situation where your 32bit iPhone is bootlooping, passcode locked, or you are unable to jailbreak it. You think all hope is lost and you must restore, updating to the latest supported iOS version. That&amp;rsquo;s not true. There&amp;rsquo;s a way to restore the iPhone without updating to the latest version of iOS, then you get to keep the currently installed iOS version and not have to worry about it ever again as long as you keep your SHSH.</description></item><item><title>Operating systems to use on old computers in 2020</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-06-02-using-old-computers-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 16:15:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-06-02-using-old-computers-in-2020/</guid><description>Introduction Here&amp;rsquo;s a hypothetical situation, imagine you are using your computer and suddenly it stops powering on. No apparent reason, it just simply doesn&amp;rsquo;t work anymore. However you do have a Pentium 4 computer sitting in your closet collecting dust. So being that it&amp;rsquo;s your only functional computer, you plug it in and power it up. It runs an operating system from many years ago, Windows XP or an old Linux distro probably.</description></item><item><title>Taking a look at ReactOS, a real open source Windows XP replacement?</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-05-14-taking-a-look-at-reactos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 11:16:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-05-14-taking-a-look-at-reactos/</guid><description>Introduction I got bored and decided to check out ReactOS, an open source alternative to Windows. It is the effort of a team who did some clean room reverse engineering of Windows and wrote their code from scratch.
Impressions ReactOS is quite good for what it is, it is quite unstable and has poor hardware support but that is to be expected. I got it to boot on a couple computers laying around the house but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the drivers to install.</description></item><item><title>Running Void Linux in Chroot on Android</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-05-06-running-void-linux-in-chroot-on-android/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 12:16:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-05-06-running-void-linux-in-chroot-on-android/</guid><description>Introduction So I decided to mess around with my Fire 7 tablet and see if I could get a chroot environment of Linux. I used Void because it is quite lightweight and is perfect for testing! Tutorial So first off this is what you will need:
A rooted Android device Linux A reasonable amount of free space (at least 8GB) Void Linux Root FS Now we can get started!</description></item><item><title>AARCH64 Arch Linux ARM on Raspberry Pi 4</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-04-10-aarch64-arch-linux-arm-on-raspberry-pi-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 12:16:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-04-10-aarch64-arch-linux-arm-on-raspberry-pi-4/</guid><description>Introduction So you may know about the Raspberry Pi, a single board computer designed for embedded applications and DIY projects. You may also know that some people use them as desktop computers. However, one of the biggest problems when it comes to the Pi 4 is poor 64bit support. There is little to none in mainline and the downstream kernel is a bit old. We won&amp;rsquo;t be fixing that problem but we will be running Arch Linux on the Pi 4 in 64bit mode, be aware that we are using an older kernel and it&amp;rsquo;s not the latest mainline support.</description></item><item><title>Running Mac OS X 10.2 in QEMU</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-03-20-running-osx-102-in-qemu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 13:14:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-03-20-running-osx-102-in-qemu/</guid><description>Introduction If you remember my old blog (it no longer exists btw), I had a post where I ran OS X 10.2 in QEMU. That got popular so I decided to rewrite it in my jekyll blog.
Tutorial First off this is what you need:
OS X 10.2 isos QEMU A computer with a reasonable CPU and enough RAM (recommended to have at least a Core 2 Duo and 4GB RAM) Command line knowledge Patience Now we can get started!</description></item><item><title>Restoring and updating iOS devices from Linux with iDeviceRestore</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-01-07-restoring-and-updating-ios-devices-from-linux-with-idevicerestore/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 13:14:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-01-07-restoring-and-updating-ios-devices-from-linux-with-idevicerestore/</guid><description>Introduction You may be a Linux user, but you may have an iPhone as well. Occasionally there will be times when you&amp;rsquo;ll need to restore and update your iPhone. You may think that because you&amp;rsquo;re using Linux you are unable to restore or update your iOS device without a virtual machine or dualboot. Thankfully this is not true. Thanks to the developers behind libimobiledevice there are new tools to do the restore and update process directly from Linux.</description></item><item><title>One year of Linux on the 2010 MacBook Pro</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2019-12-24-one-year-of-linux-on-the-2010-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 15:09:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2019-12-24-one-year-of-linux-on-the-2010-macbook-pro/</guid><description>Introduction So I got the 2010 MacBook Pro to use as a MacBook for school and on the go. I started using macOS in 2016 when I built my first hackintosh because I liked the user interface, the dock at the bottom, the bar at the top, and it looked nice together. However as I started getting into embedded development and some other stuff I quickly realized that macOS was insufficient for what I needed to accomplish.</description></item><item><title>How I triple booted my MacBook Pro</title><link>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2019-12-01-how-i-triplebooted-my-macbook-pro/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 15:09:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://alicela1n.github.io/post/2019-12-01-how-i-triplebooted-my-macbook-pro/</guid><description>Introduction Important: This has only been tested on the MacBook7,1 and MacBook Pro7,1 and I take no responsibility if something goes wrong! So I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about doing this for quite a long time. You may think well it&amp;rsquo;s just a MacBook so it can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be that hard, I mean PCs have been doing this for years. Well yes and no. Before I explain why let me just tell you a bit of back story to why I needed to do this, I&amp;rsquo;ve basically been in a situation where I need to use Windows while on the go (yes it&amp;rsquo;s rare but sometimes happens).</description></item></channel></rss>