<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>apple on Alices Digital Notebook</title><link>http://alicela1n.github.io/categories/apple/</link><description>Recent content in apple on Alices Digital Notebook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 11:12:30 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://alicela1n.github.io/categories/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Working audio in Mac OS X 10.5 (or 10.4) PPC in QEMU</title><link>http://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-08-23-osx-10.5-ppc-in-qemu-with-working-audio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 11:12:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-08-23-osx-10.5-ppc-in-qemu-with-working-audio/</guid><description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in old operating systems in a while, especially Apple ones. I love QEMU because it lets me emulate different (and a lot of obscure) operating systems and architectures that I otherwise would not have access to. This includes PPC Mac OS X, however one problem is that audio has never worked for me, since QEMU doesn&amp;rsquo;t emulate a supported sound card.
Passing through an audio device? Inconvenient, and I need to find one that is supported first.</description></item><item><title>Dumping SHSH and restoring 32bit iOS device</title><link>http://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-06-26-dumping-shsh-and-restoring-iphone-without-losing-ios-version/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 23:48:34 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-06-26-dumping-shsh-and-restoring-iphone-without-losing-ios-version/</guid><description>!This was one of my quick written guides so if you have any improvements feel free to pull request them in!
Introduction Sometimes you might be in a situation where your 32bit iPhone is bootlooping, passcode locked, or you are unable to jailbreak it. You think all hope is lost and you must restore, updating to the latest supported iOS version. That&amp;rsquo;s not true. There&amp;rsquo;s a way to restore the iPhone without updating to the latest version of iOS, then you get to keep the currently installed iOS version and not have to worry about it ever again as long as you keep your SHSH.</description></item><item><title>Running Mac OS X 10.2 in QEMU</title><link>http://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-03-20-running-osx-102-in-qemu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 13:14:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://alicela1n.github.io/post/2020-03-20-running-osx-102-in-qemu/</guid><description>Introduction If you remember my old blog (it no longer exists btw), I had a post where I ran OS X 10.2 in QEMU. That got popular so I decided to rewrite it in my jekyll blog.
Tutorial First off this is what you need:
OS X 10.2 isos QEMU A computer with a reasonable CPU and enough RAM (recommended to have at least a Core 2 Duo and 4GB RAM) Command line knowledge Patience Now we can get started!</description></item></channel></rss>